[♪ upbeat music plays]
DOCTOR ON THE EDGE
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION
SOME SCENES WERE GENERATED USING AI
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS
WERE FILMED SAFELY
[♪ mischievous music plays]
You lying bastard!
[gasps]
What are you gonna do
about my precious money?
What are you gonna do about my 15 million?
Oh, no. What do we do?
Oh, no.
Are you okay?
[gasps] Mr. Park! What are you doing?
The insurance company told me
that I have angina,
not myocardial infarction!
And they won't cover angina.
-You did this just because of that?
-"Just because of that"? Wow.
So 15 million is a joke to you?
[sighs]
When angina progresses,
it becomes a myocardial infarction.
Exactly!
So it wasn't a myocardial infarction!
You should've just given me
antacids like I said,
so I could've gone
to the hospital next morning!
Why the hell did you cause
such a scene with the chopper?
I'm out 15 million
and can't even get my insurance payout.
If I had prescribed you antacids
and let you wait to go to the hospital,
you would've gotten it.
As a life insurance payout.
-What are you saying?
-What?
[Hari] No…
Life insurance?
You goddamn quack!
Mr. Park! Let's talk it out!
-Let go!
-Let go of…
-You…
-[Hari] Mr. Park.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
We'll check on the situation first
-and…
-[Jiui screams]
We're really sorry! Just a second!
[Mr. Park] Hey!
Where do you think you're going?
You lying quack!
Give me back my 15 million!
[pants]
[sighs]
[screams]
[spits]
EPISODE 3
GETTING THROUGH ANOTHER DAY
[Ms. Hwang] Oh, my. This is bad.
Mr. Park's normally such a gentleman,
but once you get into a fight with him,
he never lets it go.
He's like a bulldog gnawing on a bone.
[growls]
[Ms. Hwang chuckles]
[clears throat]
Anyway, you're really in for it, Dr. Do.
CLIFFSIDE RAW FISH RESTAURANT
-Auntie.
-We're here.
Goodness.
I'm sorry to tell you this…
-What is it?
-[clears throat]
We're all out of ingredients.
-You're…
-What?
You're all out of ingredients?
You told us to come over
for pork cutlets just 20 minutes ago.
Exactly.
I swear everything was fine
20 minutes ago, but…
-[sighs]
-[clears throat]
-Hello, Mr. Park.
-Hello.
[Mr. Park sighs]
That's just how the world works.
Isn't it?
STYLE
::cue()
[sighs]
Just a week ago, I myself would have
never guessed that I'd be down 15 million.
You know?
I think it's because of me,
so I'll eat on my own.
We're good now, right?
-Enjoy your meals.
-[Hari] I'll go with him.
I'll see you later. [chuckles]
[Ms. Hwang] Oh, dear.
GENERAL GOODS FOR SALE
[Hari] Gosh.
Why did you come with me?
What if Mr. Park starts gunning for you?
Maybe I'll be the one gunning for him.
[chuckles] Don't worry.
[sighs]
Do you regret it?
Do you wish you'd just
pretended not to notice and let him go?
[clicks tongue]
Whether I regret it or not is irrelevant.
Because like him or not,
lacerations are lacerations?
[sighs]
I'm sure Mr. Park
just lost his temper momentarily
because of the sudden massive bill.
I'm sure he'll let up soon.
What more could he possibly do?
Hmm? [chuckles]
[yelps]
[Jiui] Turns out
there was more he could do.
Goodness me.
Thank you all
for your hard work in the rain.
You're here?
Please don't mention it.
This is the kind of work
we should be doing for our residents.
[Mr. Park chuckles] Well, lookee here.
Dr. Do Jiui.
You're a proper garbage man.
Sure would've been nice
if you had just done that from the start.
That way I'd still have 15 million.
-[staff chuckle]
-[groans]
[Ms. Hwang] Right.
[♪ tense music plays]
I can't take this anymore.
[groans]
-[groans]
-Are you okay?
What was that for?
-I thought a fight was going to--
-[Mr. Park] What?
Do you have something to say?
It's nothing. You take care now.
Of course, he has nothing to say.
Nothing to say, right?
Just try to bear with it.
I'm sure he's just frustrated.
Why do you keep telling me
to bear with it?
What did I do wrong just now?
This is the least we could do for them.
They're the residents, after all.
No.
I won't stand for this anymore.
I have no reason to!
[sighs]
[stammers, sighs]
PUBLIC HEALTH CENTER
[coughing]
Goodness. Look how inconvenient
things are for the both of us,
because you'll only prescribe me
three days' worth of medicine.
Your cough isn't getting better.
Maybe because the doctor
is bad at his job.
Do you take any other medication
or have you fallen ill before?
Let's see…
No.
Let me take a look in your mouth.
Would you say "Ah" for me?
I'll also take your temperature.
For the love of…
What's with all the prodding and poking?
Chronic coughs are a bad sign.
It might be good
to go to the mainland and get an X-ray--
Why are you so eager
to send patients off to the mainland?
I'm not a sucker like the chief!
I couldn't afford that
in my wildest dreams,
so just give me my meds now!
I'm not a vending machine
that just dispenses your medicine!
What?
STYLE
::cue()
Go wait outside.
Okay.
Allow me to explain--
Hello, ma'am. What brings you in today?
It's the same problem as always. My knees.
Your knees?
That's why I've captured these
and brought them with me.
I heard these are amazing
for aching knees.
Oh, ma'am!
What are…
-What are those?
-[chuckles]
What do you think?
I brought them for bee sting therapy.
You know how to administer it, right?
[chuckles]
Gosh, ma'am.
You're not meant to administer
bee sting therapy using actual bees.
You're supposed to refine the venom
extracted from a honeybee
and inject it using a needle.
So please put that away.
Well, damn.
That was a total waste of time and effort.
[groans]
Ma'am, you'll have to take this with you.
What use would I have for that?
It's not like I can eat it.
[sighs] But I can't eat it either…
-Ms. Eom?
-Yes?
Go take a seat and wait, please.
What is it?
[chuckles]
Would you mind putting this away for me?
You want me to put it away?
Why's that?
You think a country bumpkin like me
can handle bees with my bare hands?
N-Not exactly.
[sighs]
Fine. Your wish is my command,
your highness.
-Ooh…
-[gasps]
Cut it out.
-[exclaims]
-Seriously! I told you to cut it out!
Just get out! What's wrong with you?
-[exclaims]
-[screams]
Come on! [breathes shakily]
-[gasps]
It stings!
[exclaiming, screaming]
I'm sorry, Ms. Eom.
[sighs] What's going on?
-[Ms. Hwang] Run!
-[Jucheon] Oh, you see…
What is it?
[Jucheon stammers, yelps]
[screaming]
Run for your lives, everyone!
PUBLIC HEALTH CENTER
-That stings! Get out!
-The door!
Run!
-Stay away!
-Hurry!
-Stay still!
-Here!
Stay still!
[groans] That stings!
Why are there bees in the center?
-How on earth did this happen?
-Well…
Hold on a minute.
-What about Dr. Chiyeon?
-What?
-Dr. Chiyeon.
-Huh?
Huh?
[panting]
EXAM ROOM 2
[♪ heroic music plays]
[exclaims]
STYLE
::cue()
That stings. Come on.
Stay still.
Seriously.
Are you kidding me?
Look what they've done to my cute face.
This is ridiculous.
We got bees unleashed on us,
but Ms. Sinhye's telling us
to just stay put.
Of course, we should.
We're civil servants.
"Civil servants"?
Well, if we're civil servants,
they should at least
cover our expenses properly.
I've been buying my needles
for the past few months.
Self-funded needles!
I know they don't cost that much,
but it really grinds my gears.
-You shouldn't let that bother you.
-Why not?
Because we're doctors.
We shouldn't let money
get in the way of saving lives,
as doctors.
But still, this is a bit…
[Hyeon] It's unfair.
But we're supposed to suck it up
as soldiers.
-You said we were civil servants.
-We are civil servants.
We're also soldiers
and doctors.
Hmm…
Sounds like a fancy way of saying
we're punching bags
that the whole town can use.
That's why you shouldn't try too hard.
Nothing will come of it.
[door opens, closes]
Did something happen to him
before he came to Pyeondongdo?
Uh…
I heard he was sued by a resident
he treated before he came here.
[♪ sentimental music plays]
Someone sued him?
Two patients with puffer fish poisoning
were brought in,
but while he was treating one,
the other one apparently died of shock.
And the family of the deceased
sued Dr. Hyeon.
What? Are you…
That's ridiculous.
What's even more ridiculous
is that the person who survived
also sued him.
Why?
I guess they chose
to side with their own people
rather than the doctor
who saved their life.
-[sighs]
-Even the person he trusted
to be on his side
told Dr. Hyeon not to fight it.
This is the least we could do for them.
They're the residents, after all.
Is Ms. Hari also on the residents' side?
EXAM ROOM
Hello, sir. What brings you here--
[resident] Prescribe this for me.
-What?
-I don't have time.
So just prescribe it for me now.
GOPU SYRUP, PSEUDOPHEDINE…
[Hyeon]
That's why you shouldn't try too hard.
Nothing will come of it.
I'll write you a script.
GOPU SYRUP, PSEUDOPHEDINE
[resident] Then, since you're
writing me a script anyway--
I'll give you a lot.
Will 30 days' worth be enough?
Hot damn. That sounds great.
30-DAY PRESCRIPTION
Please wait outside.
Okay.
Wasn't expecting that.
[breathes heavily]
[Jiui] True to the name, Pyeondongdo,
where only one thing matters to them
and that is comfort,
I decided to find comfort for myself.
My insides are in a knot,
and I keep gagging.
So I'm here to pick up
some digestive medicine.
I'll write you your usual prescription.
30-DAY PRESCRIPTION
I need some pain relief patches
and some meds for my arthritis.
STYLE
::cue()
Sure. Pick them up on your way out.
I've got canker sores…
I'll prescribe some Oremedy for you.
Well, I don't care about the ointment.
I was just wondering why I keep getting
so many canker sores…
Think it's 'cause my immunity's shot?
Do you think exercise
might make them heal?
Exercise for immunity?
Sure. It's great.
You should exercise.
I'm here to get some painkillers.
Would you like Talenol or Iburonfen?
Just give me whatever.
I'll give you both.
Oh… Okay.
[coughing]
I'll prescribe you 30 days' worth.
DAYS: 30
[sighs]
[Ms. Hwang] You're right.
They're both handsome.
-Yes.
-[Jangsu] Yes.
Here's thirty days' worth of medicine.
Take them in the morning and evening,
30 minutes after a meal.
Well, damn. That's more like it.
So 3 times 1 is 3,
which makes it 11,000 won.
-[chuckles] Right.
Only take them twice a day
in the morning and evening!
-[Jangsu] Got it.
-Okay.
-Take care!
-See you next time.
[sighs]
[Hari clears throat]
Dr. Do. [chuckles]
Yes?
What's gotten into you recently?
What do you mean?
You prescribe whatever they ask for,
and you send them away so quickly.
And prescribing a month's worth
of cough medicine like that--
You told me to let them have their way.
-What?
-I was doing what you told me to do.
I know now that getting into fights
will do me no good whatsoever.
[stammers] That's not what I--
I just need to stick it out for a year,
then leave, safe and sound.
[scoffs]
Whatever happened to "Like them or not,
lacerations are lacerations?"
I guess I adjusted to life here.
I see.
I get what kind of person you are now.
What?
I almost mistook you for a good doctor.
I'm just a civil servant.
Actually, I'm not even a civil servant.
What even am I?
I'm nothing.
That's why no one will protect me!
I'm not done talking! Where are you going?
Dr. Do.
You'll have to make rounds
on Madeokdo tomorrow.
-M-Madeokdo?
-Yes.
Don't worry, though.
Ms. Yuk will be accompanying you.
[Hari] Ms. Hwang!
Can I go to Madeokdo
with Dr. Hyeon instead?
Me?
Well, this would be
our first Madeokdo visit,
so I figured it'd be awkward
for the patients
if they're unacquainted
with both Dr. Do and me.
Wouldn't Dr. Hyeon be better
since he's been there?
Oh…
But Dr. Hyeon said he doesn't want--
[Hyeon] I'll go.
You're going to go on visits?
Let's leave early tomorrow.
Sure. [chuckles]
I guess that settles that.
[Ms. Hwang exclaims]
You must be so happy, Dr. Do!
-[Ms. Hwang chuckles]
-[Jiui sighs]
What does she want from me?
[sighs]
STYLE
::cue()
PUBLIC HEALTH CENTER
CLOSED
START
RECORD, STOP
[sighs]
[♪ serene music plays]
[pants]
What the…
It's not like I said anything wrong.
Why do I have to bear with everything?
[scoffs]
[phone buzzing]
Hello?
Dr. Jiui, where are you?
The supplies we ordered are here.
Could you pick them up for us?
Thanks.
-[line disconnects]
-Hey…
I can't even…
Only take what's yours!
-Okay?
-Okay.
You don't wanna take someone else's stuff.
-This one's mine.
-Yeah.
Looking for your delivery?
Yes.
[Mr. Park] Look hard.
I've had hand tremors
ever since I lost 15 million.
I might have dropped it somewhere.
Those were supplies for the health center!
That's none of my concern,
just as my 15 million
was none of your concern.
-[scoffs]
-[groans]
Oh!
There it is.
The delivery for the Public Health Center.
On your way back,
drop off those remaining deliveries. Okay?
What?
They're all for old folks here.
Isn't it a PH doc's duty to do everything
for the health of the residents?
Isn't it?
PYEONDONGDO VILLAGE HALL
Use this if you want to.
[scoffs]
Are you sure that's yours?
What are you doing?
Ah…
I'm putting on sunscreen.
I don't want to get burned.
The sun's not even up yet though.
Sunscreen's super important, you know.
Oh…
Do you want some?
[♪ comedic music plays]
What is it?
It's nothing.
Come on. Put some on, okay?
You're meant to apply it all the time.
Early in the morning, late at night,
before bed and even during winter.
No, really. I'm good.
Don't play coy with me.
Men wear it too nowadays.
Give me your hand.
Smear it all over.
Don't miss any spots.
No… Wait!
[sighs] Damn it.
[groans] Seriously…
HANDLE WITH CARE
"Handle with care."
Yuk Ha…
RECIPIENT: YUK HARI
Ms. Yuk Hari.
HANDLE WITH CARE
STYLE
::cue()
"Handle with care"?
In the spirit of handling it with care,
I should probably let her know.
Yes, definitely.
Let's see…
Ms. Yuk, I came across your delivery
and it seemed important, so…
What the…
[groans] No!
Delete.
Come on. Delete.
THIS MESSAGE HAS BEEN DELETED
FOR YOU ONLY
No! Wait!
[gasps, exclaims]
What… What am I going to do?
[exclaims] Come on!
PYEONDONGDO, MADEOKDO, GAYEONGDO
[phone chimes]
[gasps] What the heck?
-What is this?
-What's wrong?
What?
Uh…
It's nothing.
Oh, my.
Thank you for coming.
I'm the village chief.
[chuckles]
Goodness me.
I guess you had a pretty rough trip.
You're as pale as a ghost.
-Excuse me?
-It's nothing. Come this way.
[Ms. Hwang] You brought the packages?
-Yes.
-[Ms. Hwang] Well done.
Now organize everything in there.
Organize everything too?
RECIPIENT: YUK HARI
What brings you here today?
Doctor, my boy, Juman,
normally eats like he's got a hollow leg,
but today he hasn't touched
his food all day.
Not even a drop of water.
He has a hollow leg?
He normally has a large appetite
but didn't even have a sip of water today.
Ah…
I'll need to examine the patient.
Is he not able to come here?
Oh, my.
He's here with me.
Goodness, Juman. Get out here.
-Goodness me.
-[Juman whimpers]
Please hurry and take a look at him.
I'm worried my son might be sick!
[Juman whimpers]
Goodness.
You haven't treated him yet.
Where are you going?
MADEOKDO SENIOR CENTER
That old woman, she's not exactly normal.
She's not all there.
She thinks that dog is her son
who died when he was little.
-Ah…
-[sighs]
[village chief] Gosh.
[Hari] But… [sighs]
-Oh, man.
-[sighs]
[line connects]
[Hyeon] Bro, can you talk right now?
Well, she's saying that her dog
won't eat or drink any water.
What am I supposed to do?
The weight?
Around three kilos, I think?
Okay, I'll get back to you later.
-Yeah.
-[line disconnects]
[inhales sharply] Juman…
How's Juman doing?
It's not serious, is it?
If Juman ends up passing away,
I'll follow him.
I think we should monitor him
for a couple days.
Could be he's being fussy with food,
so try giving him treats he likes.
If he eats his treats,
he's probably not sick.
Goodness, I don't know how to thank you.
Juman, thank the good doctor, okay?
Okay. Goodbye, Juman.
-[barks, growls]
-[Hyeon groans]
Are you okay?
Oh, goodness me.
[groans, sighs]
STYLE
::cue()
[sighs]
I was peeling onions for the dinner shift,
but I ended up peeling my fingers as well.
[Geumja groans]
It's a big wound and it's deep,
so I think you'll need stitches.
You should go to the mainland
to get it treated.
The mainland?
What am I going to do?
We even have a group reservation today.
[sighs] Can't I get it treated here?
[Jiui] It's a big wound and it's deep.
If she were to file a complaint
about it leaving a scar…
It's because there might be nerve damage.
You'll want to get a proper checkup.
[sighs]
[Hyeon groans]
I guess you like dogs, huh?
No.
I'm scared of them
because I got bitten once.
Really?
Then why…
Because it seemed to bother you.
Was that not the case?
[chuckles]
It's just…
She reminded me of my grandma,
and I felt bad for her since the dog
was her only source of warmth.
That's it.
I'm sorry you have to leave
before even grabbing a meal.
You even got bitten by a dog.
Uh… [chuckles]
It's fine.
How about you treat us
to a lot of good food
-on our next visit?
-Okay.
[elderly resident] Doctor!
Doctor!
Oh, no.
This is bad.
My boy, Juman…
Enough! They have to get on their boat!
Oh, gosh! He's bleeding!
He's going to die!
-Look…
-Okay, I'll take a look.
Hey,
stay still.
Let me take a look at you.
-[growls]
-What is it?
There's a splinter stuck in him.
We should remove it and stop the bleeding.
But…
But?
I'm not sure I can do it.
[growls, barks]
[♪ tense music plays]
We don't have time.
Just thirty seconds. No more.
Are you sure you can do this?
Let's do this in one go.
One.
Two.
Three. Now!
[groans]
[♪ comical music plays]
-Done. We did it!
-It's done? We did it?
-I got it out! We did it!
-We did it! [exclaims]
How's my Juman doing?
We got it out!
-[chuckles] Look!
-[elderly resident] Oh, thank you so much!
-Thank you.
-You got it out. Wow.
-[elderly resident sobs]
-[Hyeon sighs]
STYLE
::cue()
Thank you.
[groans]
[watch beeps]
Hey, when will they be returning anyway?
[Ms. Hwang] Gosh, I know.
The last boat was a while ago,
so I wonder if they got on.
-Goodness.
-[phone ringing]
Oh… [grunts]
Yes, Public Health Center.
-[Hari] Ms. Hwang…
-Hey, is something wrong?
We had to treat
an urgent last-minute patient
and missed the last boat.
[Ms. Hwang] An urgent last-minute patient?
Don't worry. We treated him well.
Then do you have a place to stay?
Yes. One of the residents here
offered a place.
[Ms. Hwang sighs] That's a relief.
In that case, good luck with that.
Mmm…
What is it?
Something urgent came up,
so Ms. Hari and Dr. Chiyeon
missed the last boat.
They'll be back tomorrow.
T-Tomorrow?
Yes.
Wow. No way.
So these things really do
happen in real life, huh?
What do you mean by that?
It's like something out of
a late '80s movie.
-A movie?
-There he goes again, talking nonsense.
[Jucheon] Get this.
A young man and woman go to an island,
and they miss the last boat.
And you know what happens next?
There's only one room available.
Only one room…
available?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[innkeeper] What to do?
There's only one room left.
Oh, my!
[Jucheon] The sky's grown dark
in an unfamiliar town.
They're saying they only have one room.
Well, I suppose it cannot be helped.
[Jucheon] They only have
each other to rely on…
[Hari sighs]
Mmm.
-[Hari sighs, gasps]
-Ms. Yuk!
We have plenty of time to spare.
Would you like a drink?
[gasps]
[Jucheon] Since things are awkward,
they naturally gravitate towards
sharing a drink together.
[loudly gulping]
[both sigh]
[Jucheon] One glass
-turns into two…
-[Hari] Cheers.
[Jucheon]
Their glasses keep touching until…
Dr. Chiyeon, I seem to be getting drunk.
Gosh.
I'm already drunk on your scent, Ms. Hari.
[Jucheon] Something else starts touching!
[Jeongseon] Something else?
[Hari gasps]
-[Hyeon hums]
-[Hari sighs]
Stop!
[Jucheon] What do you think?
Not bad, huh?
I'm gonna go to my room now.
[Jeongseon] Okay.
[Jucheon] You're going?
Things were just getting spicy.
[Ms. Hwang] Dr. Yong, you really put
too much thought into saying
a whole lot you really don't need to say.
[Jiui] My point exactly!
[Jucheon] I thought
it was super fun, though.
STYLE
::cue()
[innkeeper] What to do?
I'm sorry, but we only have one room left.
Uh…
In that case…
If it's all right with you,
would you like to stay in my room?
Oh, no. That's fine.
We're just grateful
that you're looking out for us.
That there's my room,
so tell me if you need anything.
-Okay.
We have plenty of time to spare.
Would you like a drink?
[boat engine running]
They go around just fine,
even late at night.
[Hari] Cheers.
-[Hyeon sighs]
-Wow!
Do you still not remember
the day we first met?
[Hari groans]
Sorry.
Well, that's disappointing.
It was the first time in my life
I've ever been rejected.
What?
You rejected me,
when I didn't even ask you out.
-What do you mean by…
-[motorcycle approaching]
[motorcycle crashes]
[body thuds]
[bystander] Hello? Emergency line?
I'm the one who just called
about the motorcycle accident.
Check where they are!
[bystander] Can you tell me where you are?
Yes. She's administering CPR.
I'm an intern at Yeonhui University.
I'll take over.
-Okay.
-[bystander] They're almost here!
[Hari] EMS is on the way.
The patient's breathing again.
EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICE TEAM
Good job.
You too.
Wait.
I'm sorry.
-What?
-I have a boyfriend.
-Hey, wait--
-I told you I have a boyfriend.
That's great.
I'm sure your boyfriend
will want to reach you,
-so take this with you.
-What?
This is yours.
Oh, my.
I see. How did it…
You don't seem like
love-at-first-sight material.
What?
Look in the mirror.
You'll see what I mean.
Move aside.
What's wrong with my face?
[chuckles]
[Hari gasps]
You're the guy from…
-[chuckles]
-[Hari gasps loudly]
Right?
Wow. [laughs]
I'm really not usually like that.
I was just so out of it and that was just…
-Pretty sure you're still the same.
-I'm not!
[Hyeon chuckles]
It's meant to be handled with care.
It should be handled with care.
And we wouldn't want
anyone stealing it, so…
I'll just put it over there.
[Mija] Hi, Hari.
How are things over there?
Do you have a place to stay?
Goodness. Don't worry about me.
I'll take care of myself.
STYLE
::cue()
Okay, I'm hanging up now.
[grunts]
-[Mija] Burglar!
-Wait!
[Jiui yelling]
Who are you?
Wait! It's me.
[Mija] Oh, my.
-You're the doctor.
-Yes.
What brings you here?
This. A delivery.
Delivery…
Oh, goodness.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
[Mija] Come in.
Sit here for a bit.
I'll bring the medicine.
Here.
Goodness.
Let me see.
Goodness. That's got to hurt.
[Jiui groans]
[Mija laughs]
ONE PAINKILLER
WHEN PAIN BECOMES UNBEARABLE
TALENOL
DON'T TAKE MORE THAN FIVE
But what kind of pain
is making you take so many…
I didn't even get to ask you back then.
[Mija] Well…
It's nothing.
It's just migraines.
It seems to be causing a lot of distress,
but you shouldn't just take painkillers
because you're in pain.
Don't you worry now.
I know my body--
Better than anyone else.
But even if you may think
you know your body best,
you could be wrong.
[♪ sincere music playing]
Unlock your phone for me, please.
What for?
PH DOC DO JIUI
SAVE
This is my number.
Give me a call
if you can't make it over to the center.
Goodness me.
Thank you.
[Hari] I'll sleep on this side.
You sleep on that side.
Are we really going to sleep
in the same room?
Yeah, it's fine.
There are bugs outside.
How can I ask you to sleep outside?
Let's just make do.
I didn't say
I'd be the one sleeping outside.
What?
I mean…
[laughs]
[Hari] What is that?
Did you draw a line in case I cross it?
Wow. What do you take me for?
I should ask the same of you, okay?
Don't you dare.
I'm going to be really mad if you do.
[chuckles]
[♪ amusing music playing]
[sighs]
[Hari snores]
-[Hyoen chuckles]
-[snoring continues]
STYLE
::cue()
PUBLIC HEALTH CENTER
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
Are they back yet?
Dr. Chiyeon's back.
I guess you didn't run into him.
No, I didn't.
What about Ms. Hari?
She took the day off for something.
Do you need something from her?
No, it's nothing.
[phone ringing]
This is PH doc Do Jiui
at the Public Health Center.
Hey, I'm Ko Changmok.
Excuse me?
I said I'm Ko Changmok.
Are you having any issues there?
Sorry?
I'm just calling to see
if you're having any issues over there.
Who's calling?
Someone's asking if we have any issues.
I'm up to my neck in work!
I don't have time to deal with that crap!
Tell them to stop fooling around!
I'm just asking if you have any issues.
We're a little busy right now,
so would you mind visiting the center?
-Hello? He--
-Thank you.
[laughs]
Goodness me,
our Public Health Center
seems to be busy as hell.
This is how things are between me
and our subordinates.
We've done away with all formalities.
We're comfortable with each other.
YEOPOONG-GUN
[laughs]
[narrator] A helicopter cuts its way
across high waves and islands.
Wherever the patients may be,
a helicopter is dispatched, on the double.
A mere 10 minutes
after a patient is reported,
the helicopter
begins transporting the patient
in a stunning display
of Governor Ko Changmok's
health care modernization initiative.
[chuckling]
Now, as much as it pains me
to remember it,
the image of my grandmother
grabbing my wrist
and telling me that
one had no choice but to die
if one were to fall sick on an island
is still seared into my heart.
I promised to modernize health care
in Yeopoong-gun during my term of office,
so I, Ko Changmok,
will do whatever it takes
to overhaul our helipads
so my grandmother's words
don't apply to Yeopoong-gun, everyone!
-Hey, Mr. Choi.
-Yes, sir.
That place we called just now.
Are you sure they recently used
a chopper to transport a patient?
I'm sure of it, sir.
Well, then that's no way
to respond to a call.
I mean, Director,
you said you strengthened
the emergency protocols.
-Did you not finish what you started?
-I'm sorry, sir.
Sorry just won't cut it, okay?
Be sure to punish them
to uphold discipline.
Yes, sir. I'll have a word with them.
Just to be clear,
I told you to punish them.
[sighs]
Perhaps you've fallen ill.
[patient] Of course I've fallen ill.
I'm coughing nonstop, like I told you.
Not even the medicine
my daughter-in-law got me is working.
-Right.
-[patient coughing]
I'm going to have to switch
to a stronger medicine.
STYLE
::cue()
No matter how much I take my current ones,
it doesn't seem to make a difference.
As I said before,
there's a variety of things
-that could be causing your cough…
-For crying out loud.
I told you I know all about that. [coughs]
Just get off my case
and give me stronger cough medicine.
[coughing]
I'll be taking that as a yes
and leaving now.
[continues coughing]
REVOPANSA PILL
DAYS: 30
Morning and evening,
30 minutes after meals.
-You know the drill, right?
-Yes.
I switched to a stronger medicine.
Ms. Hwang.
I'm sorry,
I received the ID photo too late.
You certainly took your sweet time.
I see Mr. Jangsu's switching his meds.
-He said he needed something stronger.
-Is he a doctor or something?
Who's he to tell us
to give him stronger meds?
[sighs] That's how it is
with everyone here.
They all know their own body best.
If he knew his body so well,
how did he end up getting a heart attack
and needing a stent?
What a load of rubbish.
A heart…
Heart attack?
[Ms. Hwang] Didn't he tell you?
Mr. Jangsu also got a stent inserted
last year, just like Mr. Park.
I never heard anything of the sort.
That wasn't in his medical records.
Scoot over.
"Stent insertion, myocardial infarction."
MEDICAL RECORD NOT FOUND
It's not here!
-I guess it hasn't been updated yet.
-[Jiui] Oh, no!
Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs
can cause side effects or death
for patients with a history
of myocardial infarction.
Is he seriously trying to ruin my life?
[on radio] Jangsu's Herbal Medicine.
Let it energize…
Mr. Lee Jangsu!
Are you kidding me right now?
[on radio] Black garlic extract
that's damn good for chronic fatigue,
also great for hangovers,
detoxing your liver, and…
Hey, Mr. Lee Jangsu!
Mr. Lee Jangsu!
[♪ upbeat music playing on speakers]
Hey…
Hey, Mr. Lee Jangsu!
Mr. Lee Jangsu!
♪ Twirl round and round ♪
PUBLIC HEALTH CENTER
♪ Till the night is over ♪
♪ Twirl round and round ♪
-Mr. Lee!
-♪ Through the night ♪
♪ And until the day goes by ♪
Hey, Lee Jangsu!
Goddamn it!
Mr. Lee Jangsu!
I'm back!
Damn.
JANGSU'S HERBAL MEDICINE
You're back?
Seriously.
Lee Jangsu!
What the… Dr. Do?
Mr. Lee, did you have
a heart attack before?
Yes. So what?
Why didn't you tell me that?
I mean, it's not like telling you
would have done any good.
It's not like
you're going to cure my heart!
For someone with a history
of myocardial infarction, NSAIDs…
[Jiui breathes shakily]
The thing is…
you could suffer side effects
if you take those drugs.
It could even kill you,
so give me the meds right now!
STYLE
::cue()
The meds you're taking right now.
Hand those over as well.
The ones my daughter-in-law got for me?
Yes, I need to know what they are.
I'll go get them. Give me a second.
And I prescribed all this
without knowing that!
[panting]
MAPRYL
An ACE inhibitor.
Just as I thought, the coughs
were a side effect of his meds.
The reason you've been coughing,
it's probably a side effect of these meds.
You have to switch right now.
Get a new prescription
from the hospital that did your stent.
Okay.
This is why…
This is why patients have to be
forthcoming about their medical history.
Even if you think you know your body well,
you need to consult your doctor first.
That's what doctors are for!
Do you understand?
I understand.
I'm going now.
Hey, Doctor!
What is it now?
Thank you.
Goodness me. Thank you.
I mean, you came running all this way
just to save my life, didn't you?
Not even my son or my daughter-in-law
would have gone to such lengths
to help me.
[wife] You're absolutely right.
Thank you so much.
I won't touch those pills
for the rest of my life,
-so don't worry about me, okay?
-Right.
Okay.
[wife] Take care.
Goodness.
[Jangsu] Maybe I should've
given him some melons.
[wife] Gosh, you're right.
Hey, Doctor.
Hello there.
I did exactly what you told me to
and did some exercise,
and my tongue's all healed now.
I should invite you over
for a meal sometime.
I see.
Now then, you should be on your way.
CLOSED FOR THE DAY
VISITING A MAINLAND HOSPITAL
DUE TO A HAND INJURY
CLIFFSIDE RAW FISH RESTAURANT
STYLE
::cue()
Gosh.
Dr. Do, are you okay?
I'll prescribe a different medicine
for Mr. Lee.
[Ms. Hwang] Right.
Goodness me.
Mr. Park, what brings you here?
[Mr. Park] Have some of this.
Oh, my!
-Goodness!
-Sorry?
Goodness gracious!
Or toss it if you don't want it.
Dr. Do.
What's going on?
I went to the hospital to look into it.
Turns out the insurance company
tried to cheat him.
[♪ emotional music playing]
They rejected the claim
for Mr. Park's stent procedure
for myocardial infarction,
classifying it as angina instead.
And I just took their word for it.
They argued that
it wasn't myocardial infarction
because there was no ST segment elevation,
but his report clearly states
that it was a non-ST-segment elevation
myocardial infarction,
so it was indeed a myocardial infarction.
That means you can claim your payout.
Right.
It may take a while,
but you can still get your payout
if you file for compensation
with the Korea Consumer Agency
and make an insurance claim.
Wow, so you went there in person
to look into everything?
-Yeah.
-Goodness me, you precious thing.
You really were trained
at a big university hospital.
How are you so smart?
This is such great news.
I should get going now.
Okay, we won't walk you out.
And…
my wife will be bringing lunch
for the center tomorrow.
I told her to bring meat dishes.
Okay.
Dr. Do Jiui…
enjoy the food, okay?
-Goodbye.
-You precious thing.
-[Hari] I did good, didn't I?
Let me prepare those.
Sure. Just how many are there?
We're gonna have ourselves a feast.
[sighs]
I'LL BE OUT FOR A WHILE
I'LL LEAVE IT UP TO YOUR CONSCIENCE
[door opening]
Were you waiting for me?
Me, wait for you?
Not at all. I was just…
[Hari] You look like
you've got something to say.
If not, never mind.
[stammering] Thank you.
[scoffs]
STYLE
::cue()
Was that so hard?
Care to join me for some beer?
Cheers.
There's something I want to ask you.
[Jiui] Mmm.
Why did you send this to me?
I actually sent that by accident.
[Hari] I had a good laugh.
Isn't it hilarious?
Delete it.
[Hari] No. I'm going to look at it
whenever I feel down.
You should also take a look
and get a laugh out of it.
Okay?
Okay.
You've had a dark cloud
hanging over your head all day.
Did something happen?
Well…
I prescribed an NSAID to a patient
with a history
of myocardial infarction today.
What?
Do they know they shouldn't take it?
That's why I ran after him
to tell him not to take it.
I see.
Because taking it might have killed him.
But here's the thing…
I wasn't worried about the patient
as I was chasing after him.
I only worried about myself.
If someone were to find out
I prescribed the wrong meds,
they could have filed a complaint,
which would lead to disciplinary action
and me getting trapped on this island.
[♪ emotional music playing]
I ran after him to save myself.
But…
the patient thanked me.
For saving his life.
I lashed out so many times
because people looked down on PH docs…
but it turns out I was the one…
who looked down on myself most.
Despite being a doctor…
I decided to do nothing.
Doctor…
come with me.
What?
-Come on.
-What? Where…
You'll see when we get there.
STYLE
::cue()
[Jiui] What on earth are you looking for?
[Hari] Just give it a second.
There's something I want to show you.
[Jiui] I get that, but what is it?
It's not something
you can come across that easily, but…
That's odd.
They should be showing up right about now.
I'm going to climb my way down now.
[gasps] Wait!
Come here!
What is it?
[Hari] Be quiet.
[gasps]
[Hari giggles]
[♪ gentle melodic music playing]
[Jiui] I've never seen fireflies before.
[Hari] Really?
-[Jiui] Wow.
-[Hari laughs]
What do you think?
Aren't they beautiful?
What did I tell you?
I told you they'd show up soon.
They're beautiful, right?
By the way, Dr. Do…
this island
and the people here are just as beautiful
when you look at them from up close.
I'm sorry to have to keep telling you
to bear with it all the time.
But you doctors are the only ones
the people here can depend on
when they get sick.
So please go easy on them. Okay?
[chuckles]
-[Jiui scoffs]
-[laughs]
[Jucheon grunts]
Dr. Chiyeon, do you want to have a beer?
[Hyeon] No, I'm going to sleep early.
I didn't get any sleep last night.
[♪ comical music playing]
[stammers] So you didn't
get any sleep on Madeokdo?
No.
Have a good rest.
[door opens, closes]
-I knew it.
-[phone pinging]
What's got everyone so worked up?
[messenger 1] Stop everything. Major PSA.
Has a nurse recently joined
any of your health centers?
Apparently, she's notorious
for being a doctor hunter!
[messenger 2] A doctor hunter?
[Jucheon] Hmm?
[messenger 3] Do you mean
the short-haired gold digger?
The one from Asong Hospital,
with the mole on her nose!
I heard about her from an older colleague.
Asong Hospital's infamous nurse
who targets doctors!
STYLE
::cue()
A nurse from Asong Hospital?
[Ms. Hwang]
Ms. Hari here is an intellectual
who used to work
in a university hospital's ER.
Not just any hospital,
but Asong Hospital… [echoing]
Could it be…
Yuk Hari?
Can I ask you something?
Mmm.
Why did you go to Madeokdo…
with Dr. Hyeon Chiyeon?
Oh.
How could I have gone there with you?
It's not within walking distance.
It's over an hour away by boat.
Ah.
So you were looking out for me.
I didn't even realize that.
But I kind of regret it.
Maybe I shouldn't have looked out for you…
and just gone there with you.
Next time…
do you want to go with me?
[♪ romantic music playing]
EVEN IF YOU THINK
YOU KNOW YOUR BODY WELL,
YOU NEED TO CONSULT
YOUR DOCTOR FIRST
THAT'S WHAT DOCTORS ARE FOR
YOU HAVE TO BE QUIET TO
SEE THE FIREFLIES
DOCTOR ON THE EDGE
So you're saying Dr. Hyeon Chiyeon is
going out with Ms. Yuk Hari, huh?
[Geumja]
You could see hearts in their eyes.
Looks like we might be having
a wedding on Pyeondongdo!
It didn't seem to be just a rumor.
[Hyeon] Does it bother you that much?
[Jiui] I had no idea
that you and Dr. Chiyeon were…
So you were scared
that I'd get my hooks in?
[Jucheon] I'm telling you,
she's definitely gotten her hooks in!
Translated by Yoon Hyuk Park